{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description":"One way to describe a language is in the form of a grammar. ",
        "question":"What is a grammar?",
        "answer": "A way to describe languages",
        "choices": ["A way to describe languages", "A way to spell sentence right", "A way to write languages", "A way to arrange words in sentence"]
      },
      "q111": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Any grammar has variables (also called 'non-terminals') and terminals. Terminals are generally strings. Variables are things that ultimately are replaced by terminals.",
        "question": "Which of these are terminals?",
        "answer": ["a", "ball", "hit"],
        "choices": ["&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "ball", "&lt;verb&gt;", "hit"]
      },
      "q121": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Any grammar has variables (also called 'non-terminals') and terminals. Terminals are generally strings. Variables are things that ultimately are replaced by terminals.",
        "question": "Which of these are variables (non-terminals)?",
        "answer": ["<noun>", "<verb>"],
        "choices": ["&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "ball", "&lt;verb&gt;", "hit"]
      },
      "q2": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Below is the example of a language. You can form any sentence using the language",
        "question":" Which sentence belongs to the example language?",
        "answer": "The ball hit the Fritz",
        "choices": ["The hit ball Frits","The ball hit the Fritz","The Frits hit ran","Ran Frits"]
        
      },
      "q2_2":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "In this example, we put <> brackets around all of the variables to make them easier to recognize.",
        "question":"What are the variables in the given grammar?",
        "answer": ["<sentence>", "<subject>","<verb>", "<d.o.>", "<article>", "<noun>"],
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;d.o.&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "the", "Fritz", "ran", "ate"]
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "In this example, we put <> brackets around all of the variables to make them easier to recognize.",
        "question":"What are the terminals in the given grammar?",
        "answer":  ["a", "the", "Fritz", "ran", "ate"],
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;d.o.&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "the", "Fritz", "ran", "ate" ]
      },
      "q4":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Grammars have a collection of productions. In this example, each production replaces a variable with some series of variables and terminals. ",
        "question":"The &lt;d.o.&gt; variable has two productions associated with it. Select two productions of &lt;d.o.&gt;.",
        "answer": ["<article><noun>", "<noun>"],
        "choices": ["&lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;sentence&gt;"]
      },
      "q5":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": " All 'sentences' in the 'language' are generated by starting with the &lt;sentence&gt; variable and using productions to reach the desired sentence. Let’s derive “Fritz hit the ball” from",
        "question":"Which variable we must start with to derive sentence 'Fritz hit the ball'?",
        "answer": "<sentence>",
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;d.o.&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;"]
      },
      "q6":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "The first step is to replace &lt;sentence&gt; with &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;subject&gt; variable to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "<noun>",
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;","&lt;verb&gt;","&lt;noun&gt;","&lt;d.o&gt;","&lt;article&gt;"]
      },
      "q7":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt;",
        "question": "What is the substitute for &lt;noun&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "Fritz",
        "choices": ["hit", "ran", "ate", "Fritz", "ball"]
      },
      "q8":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;verb&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "hit",
        "choices": ["hit", "ran", "ate", "ball", "the"]
      },
      "q9":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;d.o.&gt;? to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’",
        "answer":  "<article><noun>",
        "choices": ["&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;"]
      },
      "q10":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;article&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "the",
        "choices": ["ran", "ate", "ball", "the", "an"]

      },
      "q11":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit the &lt;noun&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;noun&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer":"ball",
        "choices": ["ran", "ate", "ball", "an", "a"]
      },
      "q12":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit the &lt;noun&gt;",
        "question":"Can we derive these sentences 'The ball hit Fritz', or 'The ball ate the ball'?",
        "answer":"Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q13":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "The reason why we can derive “The ball hit Fritz”, and “The ball ate the ball” is that grammars only focus on the correct syntax sentences.",
        "question":"Do grammars provide sentences with incorrect semantics (meaning)?",
        "answer":"Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q14":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The formal definition of grammar is G=(V,T,S,P) where V is a finite set of variables (nonterminals) T is a finite set of terminals (generally, these are strings). S is the start variable (S∈V) P is a set of productions (rules) in the form x→y means to replace x by y",
        "question":"What does x represent?",
        "answer":["Variables", "Terminals"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals"]

      },
      "q15":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The formal definition of grammar is G=(V,T,S,P) where V is a finite set of variables (nonterminals) T is a finite set of terminals (generally, these are strings). S is the start variable (S∈V) P is a set of productions (rules) in the form x→y means to replace x by y",
        "question":"What does y represent?",
        "answer":["Variables", "Terminals"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals"]
      }
    }
  }
}

